This is not war, it's extinction.
Transformers: Age of Extinction is a science fiction,
action, adventure film directed by Michael Bay.
As humanity picks up the pieces after the battle of Chicago, a shadowy group reveals itself in an attempt to
control the direction of history…while an ancient, powerful new menace sets Earth in its crosshairs.
With help from Cade Yeager, Optimus Prime and the Autobots
rise to meet their most fearsome challenge yet.
Cade Yeager, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Optimus Prime (voice), played by Peter Cullen.
Joshua Joyce, played by Stanley Tucci.
Harold Attinger, played by Kelsey Grammer.
Tessa Yeager, played by Nicola Peltz Beckham.
Shane Dyson, played by Jack Reynor.
Transformers: Age of Extinction is a 2014 American science fiction
action film based on Hasbro's Transformers toy line.
It is the sequel to Transformers: Dark of the Moon (2011) and the
fourth installment in the Transformers film series.
Like its predecessor, the film was directed by
Michael Bay and written by Ehren Kruger.
It stars Mark Wahlberg and Stanley Tucci, with Kelsey Grammer, Nicola Peltz,
Jack Reynor, Sophia Myles, Bingbing Li, Titus Welliver, and T.J.
Miller in supporting roles.
It does not feature the original human cast from the previous three films, instead
introducing a new human cast and as well as new Transformers, including the Dinobots.
In the film, inventor Cade Yeager teams up with Optimus Prime and the surviving
Autobots to investigate a manhunt involving Transformers for their hostility.
The film was released in the United States on June
27, 2014, by Paramount Pictures.
It received generally negative reviews from critics, criticizing its pacing, runtime, direction,
plot, and dialogue, although the action sequences and visual effects were praised.
The film was a box office success, grossing $1.105 billion worldwide against a $210 million production budget, making it the highest-grossing film
of 2014, the only film in 2014 to gross over $1 billion, and the tenth-highest-grossing film of all time at the time of its release.
It was followed by a sequel, Transformers: The Last Knight in 2017.
The film explores themes of sequel, alien, on the
run, based on toy, giant robot.
The tone is thought_provoking.